<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<addon id="script.ezmaintenanceplusplus" name="EZ Maintenance++" version="2026.06.30.25" provider-name="tony7bones">
  <requires>
    <import addon="xbmc.python" version="3.0.0" />
    <import addon="script.module.requests" version="1.0.0" />
  </requires>
  <extension point="xbmc.python.pluginsource" library="default.py">
     <provides>executable</provides>
  </extension>
  <extension point="xbmc.service" library="service.py" start="startup" />
  <extension point="xbmc.addon.metadata">
	<summary>A Streamlined Utility Tool for Kodi</summary>
	<description>No Bloatware, no Nonsense! Just Keep your Kodi sharp and clean with this utility tool... Now with a Custom Wizard. The "++" fork backs up and restores over Kodi's VFS, so Backup Location / Restore can point straight at a network share (nfs://, smb://) or any VFS path, not just local storage.</description>
    <language></language>
    <platform>all</platform>
    <license>The MIT License</license>
    <forum>-</forum>
    <source>https://github.com</source>
    <assets>
	    <icon>icon.png</icon>
	    <fanart>fanart.jpg</fanart>
    </assets>
    <news>
2026.06.30.25
 - One-Tap Restore is cleaner: the redundant "Pin or change a backup" row is gone (tap
   an empty slot to pin, tap a filled one for actions), and there are now 10 slots.
2026.06.30.24
 - One-Tap Restore pin labels are clean: no more doubled "Dropbox" and no raw
   "unknown" type. If a backup type cannot be guessed from its name, you are now asked
   (Full / Userdata / Not sure).
2026.06.30.23
 - Advanced Settings (Buffer Size): the "Use Optimal" button is now focused by default.
2026.06.30.22
 - Advanced Settings (Buffer Size) now has a Cancel button (a real
   three-button dialog: Use Optimal / Enter Value / Cancel).
2026.06.30.21
 - Advanced Settings (Buffer Size) reworked: it now shows your current buffer, writes
   advancedsettings.xml through Kodi VFS and verifies it saved, uses the correct Kodi
   19+/Omega cache schema, and offers to restart so the change actually takes effect.
2026.06.30.20
 - Fresh Start no longer leaves EZ Maintenance++ disabled or looking "gone" after a wipe.
   It now preserves Kodi's add-on state so the tool comes back ENABLED, re-scans add-ons,
   ends with a clear message telling you where to find it, then restarts automatically.
2026.06.30.19
 - Fresh Start now gives you a clean Kodi canvas with only EZ Maintenance++. It no longer
   tries to switch skins first (that step could hang). It wipes all other add-ons, skins,
   and settings using the same hardened wipe One-Tap Restore uses, then restarts Kodi (which
   falls back to the default skin on its own). This add-on, its dependencies, and your
   backups survive.
2026.06.30.18
 - One-Tap Restore pin management: tap a pinned backup to get Restore / Rename / Verify /
   Change / Remove. You can now give a pin a friendly name (e.g. "Golden Full") instead of
   the raw zip file name.
2026.06.30.17
 - One-Tap Restore is now a proper menu item, not buried in Settings. Open the add-on and
   choose ONE-TAP RESTORE: pick a pinned backup to restore it, or pin a new one. Restoring
   your box no longer lives under Settings.
2026.06.30.16
 - One-Tap Restore now RESTORES. Each pinned slot has a RESTORE action: it fetches and
   validates the pinned backup, and only after you confirm does it wipe this Kodi and
   restore it. The box is never wiped until the backup is downloaded and confirmed a valid
   zip. Slots now show the pinned zip name and size.
2026.06.30.15
 - One-Tap Restore (foundation): a new Settings tab to pin a specific backup (a
   network/local file or a Dropbox backup) to a slot and verify it still exists and is a
   valid zip. Replaces the old Wizard Creator. One-tap restore-from-pin is the next step.
2026.06.30.14
 - Authorship cleanup: the add-on's listed author is now its maintainer only. The
   original EZ Maintenance+ authors are credited in the project README, not in the app.
2026.06.30.13
 - Fixes the add-on not appearing in the Kodi 19+/Omega add-on browser. It now
   declares xbmc.python 3.0.0 compatibility; without it Kodi treated the add-on as
   incompatible and hid it from Program add-ons entirely.
2026.06.30.12
 - Restore is faster: removed the diagnostic full-CRC scan that was added while tracking
   down the large-backup corruption (now fixed), which added ~20s to every restore.
2026.06.30.11
 - The restore download bar now fills correctly (the total size is read from Dropbox's
   metadata, since the download is streamed without a Content-Length).
2026.06.30.10
 - The "Downloading from Dropbox" step during restore now shows a real progress bar
   (percent and MB) instead of a static "Please Wait".
2026.06.30.9
 - Fixes large-backup restore failing partway (BadZipFile: Truncated file header). A
   full backup was including a partial copy of itself under temp/, and on restore that
   entry overwrote the staged zip mid-extraction. Restore now skips the temp/ tree, and
   backups no longer include temp/ at all. This is what was breaking Apple TV restores.
2026.06.30.7
 - Restore verifies the downloaded backup is fully readable (CRC) the moment it
   arrives, before extracting, to pinpoint where a large backup can get corrupted.
2026.06.30.6
 - Restore now logs exactly how many files it extracted vs errored and verifies the
   tree on disk afterward, so a restore that does not take effect can be diagnosed
   precisely instead of silently reporting success.
2026.06.30.5
 - Restore now works on Apple TV (tvOS), not just Fire TV/Android. After extracting, it
   re-applies your Kodi settings through Kodi's own API and rescans add-ons (like the
   official Backup add-on), so the restore survives tvOS's NSUserDefaults/cache behavior
   instead of silently reverting. It now restarts cleanly (Quit) and reports how many
   settings were applied.
2026.06.30.4
 - Restore is now honest and self-checking: it verifies the downloaded backup is a
   valid, non-empty zip before extracting, reports how many items it restored, and
   shows a clear error (with the byte count) instead of falsely reporting success when
   the download came up empty. The streamed download also fails loud on a 0-byte file.
2026.06.30.3
 - Dropbox sign-in is now more secure and self-contained: it uses PKCE, so the add-on
   no longer needs (or ships) any app secret, and the sign-in QR is generated right on
   the device (no outside QR service - works on any network).
 - Long backups are more resilient: the device is kept awake during a backup, and a
   brief network stall now resumes the current chunk instead of restarting the whole
   upload.
2026.06.30.2
 - The sign-in QR is now generated for your build and ships inside the add-on, so it
   appears even when the device cannot reach an outside QR service (no external
   dependency). Falls back to a fetched QR, then the plain URL, if needed.
2026.06.30.1
 - Dropbox upload now shows a real progress bar (percent and MB) instead of a
   frozen bar, and you can cancel it; a canceled upload never touches your last backup.
 - Dropbox sign-in shows a scannable QR code: point your phone at it, approve, then
   enter the short code. No more typing a long URL on the remote (falls back to the
   URL if the QR can't be generated).
2026.06.30.0
 - Dropbox large-file uploads are now resilient on slow connections (e.g. a Fire TV
   or Apple TV wifi uplink): smaller upload chunks, each chunk retried with backoff,
   and the session resumes from Dropbox's own offset instead of restarting the whole
   upload. Big backups (100 MB and up) that used to time out now complete.
2026.06.26.2
 - Backup safety fixes: a failed Network/SMB/NFS copy now reports an error and never
   prunes your last good backup (the failed ship is no longer treated as success).
 - Keep-N rotation now orders backups by the in-name date stamp, not the raw filename,
   so a renamed/mixed-name backup set can never delete the newest one.
 - Dropbox: single-shot uploads stream from disk (no whole-file buffer); a broken
   download cleans up its partial temp file and creates the temp folder if missing.
 - Build no longer ships lint/cache cruft (.ruff_cache, __pycache__) inside the zip.
2026.06.26.1
 - All-in-one backup tool: pick a Destination - Local, Network (SMB/NFS), or Dropbox.
 - Dropbox is one-tap: Settings -> Backup/Restore -> Destination = Dropbox -> Sign in,
   paste one code, done. No app to create, no keys to type (talks to the Dropbox REST
   API directly, no SDK). Backup uploads, Restore lists and pulls straight from Dropbox.
 - Keep-N rotation: set how many backups to keep; the oldest are pruned only AFTER a new
   backup lands, so a failed run never deletes your last good backup.
2026.06.26.0
 - EZ Maintenance++ : forked from EZ Maintenance+ (aenema, peno).
 - Backup now writes through Kodi VFS: the zip is staged locally then copied to the
   Backup Location, so nfs:// / smb:// / any network share works (not just local paths).
 - Restore reads the same way: the zip list and the selected zip are pulled over VFS,
   so you can restore directly from a network share.
2026.04.05.0
 - Updated for Kodi 22
2023.01.09.0
 - Added AutoClean Cache functionality every x days at a given hour.
 - Backup always replaced the home folder reference in xml files with special://home
   Not all addons can handle this replace so it is now possible via a setting to disable this.
 - Backup Cancel didn't work. This is now fixed.

2023.01.01.0
 - Fix a fix on 2022.12.28.0

2022.12.28.0
 - Fix crash with full backup when there are foreign, like Hebrew, characters in xml files

2021.12.19.0
 - Made kodi 19 (Matrix) compatible.

2021.11.03.0
- Fix Speedtest crash.

2020.12.19.1
- The plugin was also installed under Video add-ons. Now it only is in Program add-ons where it belongs
- Clean removed some files created by Common plugin cache or StorageServer or script.common.plugin.cache at kodi startup.
  This resulted in breaking cache functionality of kodi
- Upload kodi log file to pastebin didn't always work and the first bytes were binary characters
- Made all decode calls UTF-8
- Improved ADVANCED SETTINGS(BUFFER SIZE) functionality
    </news>
  </extension>
</addon>
