<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<addon id="script.ezmaintenanceplusplus" name="EZ Maintenance++" version="2026.07.19.5" provider-name="tony7bones">
  <requires>
    <import addon="xbmc.python" version="3.0.0" />
    <import addon="script.module.requests" version="1.0.0" />
  </requires>
  <extension point="xbmc.python.pluginsource" library="default.py">
     <provides>executable</provides>
  </extension>
  <extension point="xbmc.service" library="service.py" start="startup" />
  <extension point="xbmc.addon.metadata">
	<summary>A Streamlined Utility Tool for Kodi</summary>
	<description>No Bloatware, no Nonsense! Just Keep your Kodi sharp and clean with this utility tool... Now with a Custom Wizard. The "++" fork backs up and restores over Kodi's VFS, so Backup Location / Restore can point straight at a network share (nfs://, smb://) or any VFS path, not just local storage.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <platform>all</platform>
    <license>The MIT License</license>
    <forum>-</forum>
    <source>https://github.com</source>
    <assets>
	    <icon>icon.png</icon>
	    <fanart>fanart.jpg</fanart>
    </assets>
    <news>
        v2026.07.19.5: After a restore on Apple TV, the box no longer says "this box needs attention" when nothing is wrong. It was misreading the skin's own menu-protection files as a fault. If a restore ever does leave something unapplied, the message now tells you what to do about it. The "Purge stale tvOS keys" item has been removed from the Tools menu: that repair already runs by itself whenever it is needed.
        v2026.07.19.4: A restore now KEEPS this box's name and its video cache buffer instead of taking the backup's and then asking you to fix them. The two questions that used to appear on the first start after a restore are gone. Both settings are still yours to change whenever you like, from Device Name and Video Cache Buffer in the add-on menu.
        v2026.07.19.3: Internal. The add-on clears its own stale compiled-code cache at startup, so the code that runs is always the code that shipped. Nothing user-facing changed.
        v2026.07.19.1: Internal release-checking fix. The add-on now reports a fingerprint of its own installed storage-handling code so a verification can no longer be recorded against a box running an older build. Nothing user-facing changed.
        v2026.07.19.0: A restore that switches skins now tells you. Kodi only applies a skin change when someone confirms it on screen, which cannot be answered safely during a restore, so the box reopens on its current skin. The restored skin and its settings are installed and intact; finish the switch in Settings > Interface > Skin. The next start checks and reports it. Restores that do not change the skin are unaffected.
        v2026.07.18.2: Backups saved inside Kodi's own storage now warn first - on Apple TV that area can be cleared by the system to free space, so a backup kept there may not be present when it is needed. USB, network and Dropbox destinations are unaffected.
        v2026.07.18.1: Restore accuracy - a skin setting containing a comma (a label like "Movies, HD") came back truncated, and the truncated value was then written over the correctly restored file. Values now survive exactly as archived. A setting whose ID contained a parenthesis or quote could also hang a restore behind an unexpected on-screen keyboard; such IDs are now skipped.
        v2026.07.17.7: Apple TV restore accuracy - the stray IPTV-instance cleanup during a restore no longer falsely reports 'needs attention'. It verified its deletions against a lagging system file (the same false-failure cause fixed for boot cleanup in the last release), so a perfectly good restore could report a partial one. It now checks live storage. No change to what gets deleted or kept; restores that succeed say so.
        v2026.07.17.6: Apple TV boot fix - the stale-key cleanup no longer fights the Estuary 7 skin's menu storage. It now recognizes the skin's own menu keys as legitimate and leaves them alone, verifies its work against live storage instead of a lagging system file (which made every successful cleanup look failed and re-run forever on every start), and finishes exactly once. Also fixes the log viewer and pastebin uploader silently doing nothing on a crash-damaged log: damaged logs now display and upload with the unreadable bytes marked, cancel and empty-list cases exit cleanly, and failures are logged instead of swallowed.
        v2026.07.17.5: Apple TV restore hardening. The restored skin now comes back reliably - it is written straight to storage instead of relying on a flaky on-screen confirmation. A restore that fully succeeded says "Restore Complete" with no false "needs attention", while a genuine partial loss (including on the merge/Dropbox path) is now correctly reported. Fixes a Fresh Start bug that could wipe a box then wrongly say nothing happened.
        v2026.07.17.4: Fix - "needs attention" now fires only on a genuinely broken restore (settings did not apply, IPTV could not re-enable, duplicate/stray instances, a shadowed restored file). tvOS housekeeping that does not affect the restored box is logged, not alarmed. A restore that landed cleanly says "Restore Complete". Carries v2026.07.17.1/.2/.3.
        v2026.07.17.3: Fix - a tvOS restore that fully succeeded no longer says "needs attention". The best-effort re-vectoring of restored settings into tvOS storage is now logged, not alarmed - the settings are already applied, so a partial re-vector is not a failure. Genuine problems still report. Carries v2026.07.17.1/.2.
        v2026.07.17.2: Fix - the post-restore check no longer says "needs attention" over a harmless leftover the wipe could not clear (a stale key at a path the backup does not restore shadows nothing). It now only flags a genuinely shadowed restored file. Carries the v2026.07.17.1 Apple TV skin-switch fix.
        v2026.07.17.1: Fix - after a restore on Apple TV, the skin now reliably switches back to the restored skin instead of falling back to stock. Kodi's keep-this-skin confirmation is answered robustly and verified, with retries. Carries the v2026.07.17.0 restore verification and messaging changes.
        v2026.07.17.0: Restores now finish with a plain answer instead of a report. After every restore the add-on verifies its own work (a new "Verifying backup..." step): anything the pre-restore wipe left behind is checked against the backup, and anything dangerous is fixed automatically with one silent fresh pass. Users see at most one of four simple messages - normally just "Restore Complete" - while every count, path, and detail moves to the log. "Try Again" on a genuine problem re-runs the whole restore from the already-downloaded backup (twice at most). The restored skin now comes back reliably: it is switched after all dialogs close and Kodi's "keep this skin?" question is answered automatically, ending the stock-skin surprise after a restore. A quiet self-check on the next start confirms the restored state and only speaks if something needs attention.
        v2026.07.16.1: Verified live on real hardware (Fire TV and Apple TV): full backup captures IPTV on both, restore brings it back exactly with strays swept and the IPTV client paused/resumed, and reporting is honest. No functional change from v2026.07.16.0 - this release records the hardware verification and moves publishing to CI.
        v2026.07.16.0: Full backup now truly means full: IPTV (pvr.iptvsimple) settings are captured on Apple TV and Fire TV and restored exactly as backed up, with stray instance files swept safely after the extract. Backups carry a manifest and every backup/restore/wipe reports honestly (a partial result is reported as INCOMPLETE, never "Complete"). Wipes on Apple TV clear both storage layers so old settings can no longer resurrect, a one-time cleanup removes stale hidden settings copies from earlier versions, restores briefly pause the IPTV client so restored settings stick, and a Tools menu adds "Purge stale tvOS keys" and "Verify backup archive".
        v2026.07.15.4: Apple TV: the "close and reopen Kodi" prompt now shows correctly on tvOS (it was mislabelled "Restart", which only closes Kodi there). Affects the new channel-clear restart offer and every restore/Fresh Start prompt.
        v2026.07.15.3: Clearing recently played channels now offers a Kodi restart, because the home-screen widget reads the live PVR list from memory and only reflects the cleared list after a reload.
        v2026.07.15.2: Maintenance: a "Clear All" option runs cache, packages, thumbnails and (if any) the recently played channels in one tap, and a new "Clear Recently Played Channels" clears the PVR recently-played list. Channel clearing is done with the PVR paused so it actually sticks.
        v2026.07.15.1: Backup now confirms the final backup name (with its auto timestamp) before it starts, matching the restore confirm. Cancelling at that prompt does nothing - no partial backup is written. Applies to local, network, and Dropbox backups.
        v2026.07.15.0: New: a brand-new box now gets the same two-step tune-up a restored one does (name this device, then size the video buffer for it), on the add-on's first-ever run. Boxes that already ran EZ Maintenance++ are not re-prompted by this update.
        v2026.07.14.1: Apple TV fix: the weather location now actually applies. It was written straight to disk, where a stale Apple TV settings key could silently hide it from Kodi, so the setting appeared to save and never took effect. Added a build check that fails if any code writes a Kodi settings file that way again.
        v2026.07.14.0: Apple TV fix: a restore no longer wipes your customized main menu. Kodi settings are still made durable, but an add-on's own private data is now left on disk where the add-on can actually read it (it was being moved into a store the add-on cannot see, then deleted). Also stops a restore from deleting a Siri Remote key mapping.
        v2026.07.13.6: Apple TV fix: the Dropbox sign-in barcode now renders on tvOS too. The QR is written through Kodi's own VFS so Apple TV's sandboxed texture loader can read it (it silently can't read files written by plain Python). Fire TV was already fine.
        v2026.07.13.5: Fix: the Dropbox sign-in barcode renders again on Kodi 21.3. 32-bit QR on a fresh path each time so Kodi can't serve a stale/failed cached texture. Restores the "Set up this box" menu and thin labels.
        v2026.07.13.1: New "Set up this box" menu: adds the mini KodiShare/KodiBackup sources, installs and points Multi Weather at Sacramento, and turns on the RSS ticker (the surviving Foundation setup, moved here from the retired tony7bones setup add-ons).
        v2026.07.13.0: Menu: cleaner thin Title-Case labels. Dropped the bold ALL-CAPS and forced white color so items render in the active skin's native thin font and adapt color on focus.
        v2026.07.09.1: Boot: size alerts moved off the boot path behind GUI-ready; fixed cache clean skipping dir-only levels; fixed packages count; removed dead wizard/builds machinery
        v2026.07.09.0: Fix: the post-restore setup steps were numbered backwards. The device-name question is asked first, so it is now labelled 1 of 2, and the video-quality question 2 of 2.
        2026.07.08.6
        - Fix (Apple TV only): after a restore, Kodi's File Manager no longer lists every
        settings file twice in the profile folder. On Apple TV a restore has to copy your
        settings into Apple's private store so they survive a reopen, and it was also leaving
        </news>
  </extension>
</addon>
